KYLE HENDERSON

kylethenderson@gmail.com github.com/kylethenderson (931) 267-3804

SUMMARY

Tenacious and inquisitive full stack software engineer with several years of web application development experience. Dedicated and organized problem solver that finds motivation through building projects and discovering the inner workings of any task. Passionate about building solutions that move people and our planet forward.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React
- HTML
- CSS
- Material UI
- JavaScript
- PostgreSQL
- AJAX
- Axios

- Redux
- Node.js
- Express
- Vue.js
- Vuex
- Vuetify
- MongoDB
- Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

April 2019 - Present

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis - Full Stack Software Engineering Student

- Architected and developed CleanUP MeetUP
 - Mobile application to target and encourage local community clean up
 - Using GoogleMapsAPI, users are able to mark littered areas, communicate with others, and organize clean up efforts
 - Technologies used during development include React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, GoogleMapsAPI, and Twilio
- Leveraging software background to accelerate peer learning curve
- Consulting on design, development, and deployment of peer applications

November 2017 - April 2019

Independent Web Developer

- Designed and developed cross-browser compatible web-based solutions for multiple companies including Swift Logistics and Knight Logistics
- Utilized several technologies including JavaScript, jQuery, Vue.js, HTML, and CSS to build the front-end for internal facing applications
- Partnered with Agile development teams to integrate frameworks into internal applications

March 2016 - March 2019

Everson Logistics, Phoenix, AZ - Co-Owner

- Owner and operator of Third Party Logistics provider for online retailers
- Created custom shipping solutions catered to small businesses
- Warehoused and shipped products sold through clients' eCommerce platforms
- Managed recurring shipments alongside daily sales

November 2013 - March 2016

TIBA Putt, Phoenix, AZ - Creator/Owner

- Designed and developed golf training product utilized by PGA and LPGA touring professionals
- Increased sales 100% year over year stemming from high customer satisfaction
- Oversaw entire lifecycle of manufacturing process
- Built brand awareness through networking and grassroots marketing campaigns

July 2007 - April 2012

Swift Transportation, Phoenix, AZ

March 2011 - April 2012

Fleet Manager

- Managed over 100 dedicated OTR drivers for time sensitive tour and trade show freight
- Operated fleet with high level of customer satisfaction leading to a 600% increase in awarded tour business

August 2009 - March 2011

ECT Lead

- Assisted management with hiring and training new ECT Driver Managers
- Resolved escalated driver issues
- Built automated scripts to increase efficiency and accuracy for load tracking customer service reps

July 2007 - August 2009

ECT Driver Manager/CSR/Planner

- Handled phone calls and messages from drivers across the country
- Tracked customer loads hourly to ensure on time service
- Created transportation solutions to fulfill customer and driver commitments

EDUCATION

Expected Graduation - August 2019

Prime Digital Academy - Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

September 2001 - May 2003

Tennessee Technological University, Cookeville, TN

Completed courses towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science including:

- VB Programming
- C Programming
- Web development

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Built and managed multiple online forums utilizing vBulletin and MySQL